<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.0 OMG" xml:id="vsipl_dda"
      xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>VSIPL DDA Additions [DRAFT]</title>

    <subtitle>Version 0.12</subtitle>

    <titleabbrev>VSIPL DDA Additions 0.12 [DRAFT]</titleabbrev>

    <pubdate>
      <?dbtimestamp format="Y-m-d"?>
    </pubdate>
  </info>

  <preface role="not.in.toc" xml:id="title1">
    <!-- FIXME: DB requires a title but the OMG spec doesn't allow one. -->

    <title/>

    <para>
      <remark>This document contains proposed additions/ modifictaions to
      version 1.4 of the VSIPL specification, namely the addition of a direct
      data access (DDA) API.</remark>
    </para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">OMG Document Number:</emphasis>
    mars/13-08-02</para>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">Normative reference:</emphasis>
    http://www.omg.org/spec/VSIPL</para>
  </preface>

  <toc/>

  <preface role="not.in.toc">
    <title>Revision History</title>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.5</revnumber>

        <date>6 Sept 2013</date>

        <revremark>Initial public release</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.6</revnumber>

        <date>5 Dec 2013</date>

        <revremark>Added fields to the vsip_dda_layout structure; changed the
        definition of VSIP_DDA_SYNC_POLICY_INOUT to leverage the IN and OUT
        policies.</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.7</revnumber>

        <date>22 Dec 2013</date>

        <revremark>Added storage format and dimension order types; updated the
        layout attributes to use the new types; change the layout attributes
        to a type-agnostic type</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.8</revnumber>

        <date>23 Jan 2014</date>

        <revremark>Copied the structure of chapter 2 to the draft; Split block
        layout types out into a separate section; Added an abstract pointer
        object for complex DDA pointers, with raw pointer accessor functions,
        and modified the complex pointer accessor accordingly; added more text
        to describe the storage format type; Made synchronization policy
        declarations constant; Added dimension type declarations; Packing and
        layout types no longer have DDA-specific names; shortened dimension
        type names</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.9</revnumber>

        <date>27 Jan 2014</date>

        <revremark>Moved the DDA API out into a separate chapter, left the
        block layout types in with the VSIPL types; Clarified the language
        with respect to the return value of the datagetattrib function; Added
        block length to the proxy object attributes in place of the view
        attributes; Removed the abstract pointer type and simplified the
        complex pointer accessor API accordingly.</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.10</revnumber>

        <date>4 Feb 2014</date>

        <revremark>Changed DDA objects to be built on top of view instead of
        blocks; Added a comment for discussion RE creation of the tuple type;
        Added a replaceable character "k" to type and function definitions to
        account for the associated view type.</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.11</revnumber>

        <date>5 Feb 2014</date>

        <revremark>Changed the name of the vsip_tuple type to vsip_dim_order;
        Added comments for consideration to the vsip_storage_format and
        vsip_cmplx_mem type definitions; Added a comment for consideration to
        the vsip_dim_order type definition; Added a table to the
        vsip_sync_policy type explanation to summarize the data flows and when
        to use each policy; Added a comment for consideration to the
        vsip_pack_type section.</revremark>
      </revision>

      <revision>
        <revnumber>0.12</revnumber>

        <date>14 Feb 2014</date>

        <revremark>Reverted the vsip_cmplx_mem type definition; Updated the
        vsip_storage_format definition to use the vsip_cmplx_mem values;
        Removed the table from the vsip_dda_sync_policy section so that the
        contents match those of the corresponding section in the VSIPL++
        specification; Added aliasing rules, matching those in the VSIPL++
        specification, to the synchronization policy section; Defined
        additional type-specific function prototypes; Removed TODO statements
        from example source code files; Added TODO statements to capture
        forward-looking and out-of-scope issues for the next RTF.</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  </preface>

  <xi:include href="types.xml"/>

  <xi:include href="dda.xml"/>
</book>
